Keerthana Dixit A

Technical Recruiter - Microsoft Corporation India Pvt Ltd

Highly driven recruiting professional with 5.2 years of experience working in Human Resource. Excellent background in effective recruiting strategies for a dynamic workforce. Dedication to reach out the right talent and incorporating objectives like interviewing, hiring & sourcing. Strong leadership skills in candidate engagement and driven to work for an organization. Commitment to results that provide capable, motivated and successful candidates for employment. Well versed in Stakeholder Management, Negotiation, Screening, Sourcing, Market Mapping, Placement & On-boarding.

Personal Info

Address

No 1144, Shanthi Nivas, 1st Floor, 22nd Cross, BSK 2nd Stage, Bangalore, Karnataka - 560070, India

Phone

+91 9538731388

E-mail

keerthanadixit7@gmail.com

Date of birth

1991-08-08

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/keerthana-dixit-a-91a217159

Skills

Time Management, **Problem Solving**

Quick Learner,

Ability to Teach and

Mentor

Persuasion, Team

Building

Good

Communication

Languages

English, Kannada, Hindi, Telugu, Tamil & Malayalam -Learning Spanish



Experience

2019-08

2015-05 -Recruiter I

Amazon Development Center India, Human Resource

Role and Responsibilities:

- Sourcing Strategies: Includes social Media and aggregator tools such as LinkedIn, Naukri, Indeed, GitHub, Facebook and Twitter, Internal Hiring Tools - ICIM's & Amazon Hire. Also maintain a Passive Candidate database for future requirements and Applicant Tracking Systems (ATS).
- Talent Mapping
- Boolean Searches
- Employee Referrals Campaigns, Booths, Emailers, Floor walks, Poster and Whatsapp groups
- Sourcing candidates from within organization like Internal Job Portals
- Building Employer Brand
- Lead Generation
- Managed and gained a deep understanding of the client organization, assessing the needs of their mandate and identifying the specifics of the position to be filled.
- Highly responsible for associate level talent acquisition, volume-hiring programs, university recruiting programs, procedure and plans.
- Managing End to End recruiting from Entry level to Mid-level hiring. Screening potential candidate profiles and then briefing the candidate regarding the opportunity being offered by the client. Handled oversight, interviewing, documentation of the candidate.
- Managing engagements with candidates, with extreme professionalism and enabling the creation of long-term associations. Worked with multiple internal stakeholders and Tech BU like AWS, Software Developers, Support Engineers, Product Managers, and Quality Assurance Engineers and Non-Tech BU like Human Resources Services, Advertising, Sales, Media, Marketing, Operations, Finance and Niche Roles.
- Meet established metrics for sourcing, interviewing/assessment, offers and hires as related to level, position and business group. Also maintain data at all level of recruitment stages along with accept/decline data on offers extended and meets goals on number of annual hires relative to level and metrics.
- Assisting the client in salary negotiations with the candidate if required; also assisting the candidate in understanding the organizational or compensation structure or any other related que.
- Interviewed potential job applicants and partnered with management to select the final candidates for each open position.
- Ensuring peripheral arrangements such as interview times, dates, etc. are in place & communicated to all relevant parties involved.
- Building and maintaining a relationship with the client and acting as a one point contact for all search related queries by client.

Achievements:

- I placed and supported 10-12 business in the last 6 months
- I met and over achieved my target by 41% with in end of the year
- Achieved and hired 30+ candidates in lateral hiring alone
- Successfully hired 800+ candidates across various different business domains every year including lateral hiring. The metrics includes diversity hiring, candidate experience, 2&5 promise - (Phone Screen to Onsite Interview feedback for



candidates).

- Supported multi-location hiring for the role of Sales Associate based out of Delhi, Mumbai & Kolkata.
- 45% of high volume hiring also included campus hiring from Pan India Location.
- Oversaw 89% increase in volume hiring during the period of 2016 & 2017. Hired 1000+ candidates for Bangalore location alone with out agency support.
- Drove multiple programs to bring in participation for employee referral this was also done through ER Campaigns, Mailers, Whatsapp Group etc.
- Launched a program focusing on Candidate Experience of New Hires.
- Cut lead time for recruiting by 46%. Raised ER participation by 79%

Skills:

- Handled all recruiting duties and responsibilities in a fast-paced e-commerce industry. Recruited, interviewed, and on-boarded more than 50-80 employees every month.
- Enhanced incentive structure, Increased employee retention by 18% through lean interviewing techniques, lowered interviewing costs by 15%.

SOFT SKILLS HARD SKILLS MORE HARD SKILLS

Emotional Intelligence Recruiting Compliance

Communication Onboarding Data Analysis

Collaboration Employee Relations Evaluations

Ethics Screening JD

Organization Social Media

Problem Solving Performance Management

Negotiation

Projects:

- Part of core committee team of publishing monthly Hiring Newsletter for both Hyderabad and Bangalore location.
- Implemented a project on Process Improvement named Project Accelerate for high volume hiring and 2&5 promise of Candidate Experience

2020-01 present

Technical Recruiter

Microsoft Corporation, India Pvt Ltd (Ushta-Te Consultancy Services LLP)

Roles & Responsibilities:

Talent recruitment and sourcing professional with experience developing and executing recruiting plans within both agency and in-house settings. Manage all phases of full-cycle recruiting, from initial sourcing and screening through offer negotiations, placement and onboarding for both external and internal candidates. Creatively source high-caliber candidates by leveraging recruiting software, social media, cold calling and employee referrals.

Recruiting Tools:

LinkedIn Recruiter | Monster Talent | Naukri | ICIM's | Stackflow | GitHub | InstaHire | Goggle Searches using X-ray & Boolean | Facebook |

- Source, screen, and qualify candidates for active requisitions and develop a network of potential talent through ongoing relationship management
- Assists in development of techniques to improve candidate satisfaction and quality of service
- Develop, execute, and drive tactical sourcing strategies aimed at generating candidate flow for open positions and talent pipelines for all functions
- Develops, determines, and executes sourcing strategies and processes for searches through successful completion
- Create and execute sourcing plans that utilize numerous alternative search strategies to activate & engage passive and active talent
- Partner and prepare target list with Hiring Mangers to provide support and develop a sourcing strategy for each requisition and pipeline for the project
- Diversity and Inclusion Hiring focused on diversity-oriented sites (Jobs For Her) &

Blogs

- Utilize advanced search techniques including Boolean and X-Ray search on LinkedIn, social media, job boards, participation in networking events, and employee referrals to uncover high quality underutilized talent pools
- Ongoing research of competitive landscape and market insights/trends and remaining current and relevant in functional expertise and demographics
- Provide subject matter expertise in sourcing techniques, technology, and strategies by utilizing industry associations and professionals
- Follow a funnel-based approach to develop pipeline across multiple roles and metric driven scorecard to measure success
- Full life-cycle recruitment across multiple levels
- Check references and extend offers including external and internal candidates
- Support building and managing comprehensive oversight and outstation recruiting for different technologies
- Partnering with different BU's Customer Service Support, India Global Delivery and Engineering to hire for positions such as Support Engineers, Escalation Support Engineers, Architects, Software Developers Full Stack, Front End & Back End, Quality Engineers etc. for teams like Azure, Infrastructure, Microsoft Teams, Windows, Outlook, Share Point etc.
- Partner and influence cross-functional stakeholders within the internal recruiting process
- Successfully deliver on all deadlines and flawlessly execute in a fast faced environment

Collaborated with client hiring managers throughout the selection process to provide services including:

- Talent Pool Sourcing
- Reference Checks
- Candidate Pre-Screening
- Detailed Job Description

Achievements:

- Achieved and hired 17 candidates within 3months of joining for various technologies
- Fostered lasting client relationships as a trusted hiring partner with 89% jobfulfillment rate
- Achieved 2 PWD hires
- Successful hires of at least 22% through passive sourcing

Skills:

SOFT SKILLS HARD SKILLS MORE HRD SKILLS
Emotional Intelligence Recruiting Compliance
Communication Onboarding Data Analysis
Collaboration Employee Referrals Evaluations
Ethics Screening JD

Organization Social Media

Problem Solving Performance Management

Negotiation

Projects:

- Undertook a project based on 3E Learning & Data Metrics ICIM's Recruiting Tool which focuses on Disposition of Reqs, Candidates Detail Tab & Requisition Qualification Tab
- Part of PWD (People with Disability) hiring, and events organized by Karnataka State Govt Recruitment associated with Microsoft
- Part of Springboard Hiring focused on program for Women on Career Break conducted by One India
- Projects based on Diversity sourcing focused specifically on passive candidates

Education

2013-06 -

Christ University, Master in Applied Sociology

2015-04

- My internship experience included working with Human Resource Team at company "Convergys"
- Excelled in Human Resource coursework
- Energetically participated in various CSR activities and Cultural Programs

Certificates

Achieved Best Performer Award for Q1-Q3 (Consecutive Years 2017, 2018 & 2019) - Amazon

Candidate Experience Award (2018) and Stakeholder Management Award for High Volume Hiring (Q1- 2019) - Amazon

Achieved Award for Best Candidate Experience and Performer Award for Q1 (2020) - Microsoft

Conferences

• Conducted in class training workshops and part of HRM- Learning and development module • Conducted Employee Relation workshops for various different business •Tech MeetUps & WIT

Interests

Great Lover of Nature and Traveling, Interests towards different cultures and cuisines , Instagram Fashion Influencer, Fitness and Yoga